翻译修改，字幕时间轴调整：安德鲁基恩
妙探出差
（底特律）
这批货很好，肯定他妈的能赚钱。 -Truck looks great.
- There must be a fuckin' fortune here.
我知道，别在他面前说，好吗？
- Not in front of him, all right? - No problem.
告诉我，怎么了，老兄？怎么了？靠。我等了很久了，告诉我。 Tell me, fellas. What's
goin' on?.Shit. I been here too long. Talk to me.
-等一会 -不，来看看这个 - Give us a minute.
- Check this out.
没问题的，看看吧 no problem.look it
这是很受孩子们欢迎的卷烟。知道这是什么吗？这是联邦印花，你没法有比这更干净的了, 谈一下吧 This is a popular cigarette with the children. You
know what this is? This is a federal tax stamp.You can't get no cleaner than that. Talk to me.
如果是他妈这么棒，为什么你不要了它呢? Why don't you go into
business yourself if this is such a great deal?
我想, 但我不是来自底特律的, 我不知道谁能应付这么大的任务.你们该有门路的, I would, but I ain't from Detroit.I
don't know who could handle a job this big. You have the connections.
告诉我些, 我是个生意人, 我要坐下, 随你们怎么做吧 Tell me something. I'm a
businessman.I'm gonna sit down. Do what you want.
-它不容易脱手的 -我明白，我是个生意人 - It ain't easy to get rid of this shit.
- I know. I'm a businessman.
This is my thing.I'm doing business here.
这是我的事。我在这儿做生意。
去发动卡车，我们离开他妈的这儿. Go warm up the
truck.Let's get the fuck outta here.
-来吧，给你... 那就是我说的 -你是个机灵小子, 我喜欢你. - That's what I'm talking about.
- You're a sharp kid. I like you.
I appreciate it. Cousin, my man,
don't dash yet. 我很感激。表兄，老兄，别走
这像是只有两千块给我，这看起来不像五千块 This is like two grand to me.
This doesn't look like $5,000.
-给我, 让我看看 -这批货值五千块, 那才有两千 - Gimme that. Let me see that.
- The bill's for $5,000. That's two.
你知道吗?气死我了，我告诉我的手下要五千块的， You know what? This
pisses me off.I told my people five grand.
-但看看, 他们骗我们 不是，他们骗你，我要我的钱 - Look at this shit. They stiffed us.
- They stiffed you. I want my money.
婊子养的, 现在你没法指望任何人 ，不过我跟你说, 我们现在别他妈的争论了. Son of a bitch, you can't count on anybody today.
But I tell you what... let's not fucking hassle about it now.
你先拿这两千块，下次我再支付给你 Take the two grand, and
on the next score, I'll make it up to you.
别耍我，耍别人去，这是废话 Don't jerk me off. Jerk
somebody else off. This is bullshit.
我要五千，不是两千。别这样对待我 I need $5,000, not $2,000.
Don't do this to me.
别无理取闹，你没法对付强尼布那那 Don't be unreasonable.
You're not dealing with Johnny Bananas.
我不知道什么强尼布那那，但我可否要我的钱？
I got no idea what Johnny Banana...
我慢慢地跟你说，我要五千块，五千块, 看我的嘴巴, 五千块, 那是我需要的。 Can I say it slow for you?
I need $5,000. Read my lips.$5,000 is what I need.
这是狗屁，没钱什么都不行 This is bullshit here.
I can't do nothing with that.
你要做混蛋就自己抽光它们吧 If you want to be an asshole,
take the whole load and smoke 'em yourself.
我不抽好彩，我抽加长剑牌 我给你我的回答，我没法自己定价格。 - I don't smoke Lucky Strike. I smoke king-size Kent.
I got people I gotta answer to. I can't make a price on my own.
该死，跟你合作真好 Fuck this. Nice
doin'business with you, kid.
嘿，伙计，你们在这儿干什么？
Hey, buddy, what you doing here?
长官，你知道几分钟前发生了什么事吗？你不会相信的来看看这个 Officers, you know what happened
a few minutes ago? You won't believe this Check this out..
货车开不动，伙计，它停了。你可有充电电线，帮我一下？ The truck... it just stopped, man.Just stopped.
You got some jumper cables?.You give me a jump?
-我认识你吗？ -不，我从水牛城来的 Hey, don't I know you from some place?
No, that ain't me. I'm from Buffalo.
你们俩家伙，拿身份证出来
Both you guys, break out some I.D.
我们快他妈的离开这里
Let's get the fuck outta here!
Ah, shit. What the... 哦，靠。这...
（蔬菜）
回来！
该死 Aw, shit.
别动，混蛋！ Freeze, asshole.
福里，我们早该知道
Foley, we should've known it was you.
嘿，阿克塞尔，就该这么做！
Hey, hey, Axel, way to go.
我不明白。 我没有时间给你，杰弗瑞。 - I don't understand.
- I don't have time for you, Jeffrey.
陶德要找你，他很生气，他说这是你最糟的一次 Todd's lookin' for you. He's pissed.
You know what he said? This is your worst fuckup ever.
我个人不同意，他当时又不在场 我知道了，杰弗。谢谢。 Personally, I don't think that's
true.- He's not in there. - I can see that, Jeff. Thanks.
如果你抓到他们，他可能不会这么生气，但我听说你搞价钱被捉住了… If you'd busted these guys, maybe he
wouldn't have been so mad. I heard you got caught up haggling for money.
两千块是不够的，如果我拿了它，他们会知道我是警察 $2,000 wasn't enough money.
If I tookit, they'd have known I was a cop.
别烦我... 别走开... 你这个混蛋
Don't go anywhere. You are asshole
我不是说你做错了, 但若你抓到他们就会好一点 I'm not saying you did anything
wrong.lf you had busted them, it would've worked out better.
-你去哪里？ -拿我的屎离开这里 - Where you going now?
- Get my shit and get outta here.
大错特错，要我的意见吗？ -不要 No, big mistake,
big mistake.Want my advice?
知道如果我是你我会怎么做吗? 我不知道.
- Know what I would do if I was you? - I don't.
进去跟他谈谈，等着他, 他很快回来 杰弗瑞，走开，不然我开枪射你 Go in there, talk to him, wait for
him.He'll be right back. Get away from me. I'm gonna shoot you.
我不是要教你怎么做，不过你知道我会怎么做吗? I'm not telling you what to do.
But you know what I would do?
不要生气，我不想听你说，行吗？ Just lighten up.
I'm not listening to you, okay?
你会令自己更糟糕
You're making it a lot worse for yourself.
-看这个，谢谢你们 -阿克塞尔，你有香烟吗？ - Look at this. This is great. Thanks.
- Hey, Axel, you got a cigarette?
-那是你写的吗？ 那就是我要告诉你的.那不是秘密-大家都知道那宗货车事件 - Did you write that one?
- That's what I'm telling you.lt's not a secret. Everybody knows about you and the truck.
-杰弗瑞, 你听我说好吗？ -我不想听, 我忽视你 Jeffrey, will you listen to me?
I am not listening to you. I'm ignoring you.
听著…好极，真成熟
Great. Great.Real mature.
我不要听杰弗瑞说，但他还在说 I am not listening
to Jeffrey, but he's still talking.
-我不要听 -我讨厌你这样做 - I am not listening to you.
- I really hate when you do that.
-那么住口吧, 好吗. -那是孩子气.
- Then stop, all right. - It's childish.
该死的福里是否在这里？ 哦, 靠
- Is that fuckin' Foley in here? - Oh, shit.
陶德来了，该有好戏了
There's Todd. It's show time.
老板, 我知道你要说什么…
Boss, I know what you're gonna say...
你干嘛没有我批准就去做内应？ Where do you come off
going undercover without authorization?
这他妈的都是怎么回事儿?你要做牛仔警察 What the fuck is this
all about?.You wanna play cowboy cop?
去别的警区做好了 Go do it in
somebody else's precinct. 72
-想听我这方面的故事吗？ -什么他妈的你这方面的故事？ - You wanna hear my side of the story?
- What's your fuckin' side of the story?
让我们听听你这方面的故事。 我没兴趣再他妈的对你多说。 - Let's hear your side of the story.
- I'm not taking any more of your shit.
知道你这种惊人的举动令本市损失多少钱？ You know how much this
stunt of yours is gonna cost the city? 77
我认为不是钱的问题。长官，我认为问题是我公然违反纪律。 I don't think cost is the issue here, sir.I
think the issue should be my blatant disregard for proper procedure.
该死，你说得对，聪明货
You damn right, wiseass.
市长打电话给局长，他就打电话给副局长，副局长就来骂我的屁股 The mayor called the chief.The chief
called the deputy chief. The deputy chief just chewed my ass out.
你看我还剩下点儿什么，啊？ You see I don't have
any bit of it left, don't you?
你他妈的从哪儿弄来一卡车香烟？ Where in the fuck did you
get a truckload of cigarettes from anyway?
从迪尔伯恩抢劫案拿到的
From the Dearborn hijack.
From the Dearborn hijack?.That fucking bust
went down last week. 从迪尔伯恩抢劫案？-那辆车上周他妈的被充公，
-该被扣押在汽车场里 -我试过告诉你。 - That truck should be in the pound.
- I tried to tell you.
-这不关你他妈的的事 -这个不是我的储物柜 - This is none of your fucking business.
- This is not my locker.
听著，阿克塞尔，不准再设圈套，明白吗 Listen, Axel, no
more of these setups, you understand?
你是个很有潜质的好警察，但你什么该死的事都不懂， You're a good cop.You got great potential...
but you don't know every fucking thing.
我厌倦替你顶罪，再有一次，你就滚到街上去，明白吗？ I'm tired of taking the heat for your ass.One
more time, and you're out on the street. Do you understand me?
-老板…我告诉你... 你听懂了吗！ - Look, Boss, let me tell you...
- Do you understand me?
是，我知道了，老板...
Yeah, I understand. Boss.
局长没有把它咬光，你还有一点屁股剩下 The chief ain't chew it
all out.You still got a little ass there.
别他妈的闹了，阿克塞尔，快回家去 Don't fuck with me, Axel.
Not now. Go on, go home.
- 嗨
- Hi
-你好吗？ -很好 Hey, my man.- How you doin'?
- All right.
你还要闯入人家的屋里 I see you're still
breaking in people's houses.
你那个锁有什么用？为什么你不买个他妈的真正的锁呢？ What do you expect with that lock?
Why didn't you buy a real lock?
我不需要锁，我有枪，我会射人 I don't need lock. I got my pistol.
I pop a cap at somebody.
我负担不起电费。关上冰箱，蟑螂会跑进去 I can't afford no electrical bill, though.
Close my refrigerator. You got roaches and shit all inside there.
-坐下，伙计，看看你。 怎么了？
- Sit down, man. Look at you. - Yeah.
-你何时出来的？ -六个月前 - When'd you get out?
- I walked out six months ago.
六个月前出来你现在才来看我？ You got out six months ago
and you're just comin' to see me now?
我行为良好，提早一年出狱我去了加州享受阳光 Woody got me out a year early for good time...
and I went out to California to get some sun.
我有样东西给你看，我没见你两年了，
I got to show you something.I ain't seen you in two years.
伙计，怎么了？ Man, what's up?
一万德国马克
Ten thousand deutsche marks.
-德国马克？ -是的
- Deutsche mark? - Yeah.
-这是什么？ -无记名债券，追查不到的 - What is it?
- They're bearer bonds. Untraceable.
-你偷回来的？
-不是
-You stole 'em?
-no
我不想听，抱歉我问了 I don't wanna hear it.
I'm sorry I even asked.
-很高兴看到你，伙计，我很想念你 是，想念你
- It's good to see you, man.I missed you, man. - Yeah. I missed you.
你到加州来干什么？
What were you doing in California anyway?
我在工作 -在哪里工作？ -猜一下 - I was workin'.
- Workin' where? - Guess.
-不知道，哪里？ -比佛利山 - I don't know. Where?
- Beverly Hills.
-做什么？ -你不会相信的 - What were you doin'?
- You ain't gonna believe this, man.
- 什么？ - 我是个保安员 - What?
- I was a security guard.
谁他妈的雇用你做保安员？ Who the fuck's gonna
hire you as a security guard?
珍妮桑玛斯 -珍妮桑玛斯？ Jenny Summers.
我好几年没见过珍妮了，她怎么样？ I haven't seen
Jenny in years.What's she up to?
她很好 She's doin' great.
她是比佛利山霍利斯本顿画廊的经理 She's the manager of the
Hollis Benton Art Gallery in Beverly Hills.
它像是个举世闻名的地方，你以前听说过没有？ It's like a
world-famous place.You ever hear of it?
听过，我所有的艺术品都在那里买的
Yeah, I buy all my art there.
八号球，台角袋，中两个
Eight ball, corner pocket, two cushions.
-五十块赌你做不到 -胡说
- Fifty bucks you don't make that shot. - Bullshit.
-一百块 -好的 - A hundred.
- You got a bet.
-你会怎么做？ -你一直都这么聪明 - What are you gonna do, huh?
- You're just as bright as always.
20、40、60、80…拿去开派对吧 Twenty, forty,
sixty, eighty... Take it. Have a party.
很高兴跟你交易
Pleasure doing business with you.
你打算他妈的怎么做？
What the fuck you gonna do?
小姐，再来两杯威士忌加苏打
Miss, excuse me, two more Scotch and sodas?
我有个好主意，我们去偷车吧 I got a great idea. I
got a great idea. Let's steal a car.
你开玩笑吗？我是个他妈的警察，我不能再偷车了。你怎么回事儿？ Are you serious?.I'm a fuckin'
police officer.I can't steal cars no more. What's wrong with you?
记得那次我们偷的那辆车吗？伙计，一辆他妈的卡迪拉克 Remember the time
we stole that car, man? A fuckin' Cadillac.
我们像两个该死的疯子在高速公路上飞跑 We had to go and drive it
on the expressway... like two fucking maniacs.
我还记得你因此而坐牢 I also remember you had to
go to jail for hidin' that shit too.
那不是监狱，那是公立学校，当你15岁时，公立学校就是监狱。 That wasn't jail. It was a state school.
A state school is jail when you're 15 years old.
不算是坐牢，伙计，比起监狱那像是日间夏令营 Not jail, man.
That's like day camp compared to jail.
为何你被拘捕时没有告发我？我们可是一起的 How come you didn't tell on
me when you got caught, that we were together.
你不知道？ You don't know?
-你不知道？
-不知道
- Really?
- No.
因为我爱你 Because I love you, man.
再来一杯 One more round.
别动，迈克 我要开门，好吗？ Hold still, Mike.
I gotta open the door, okay?
站住了，好吗，开始了。
Balance yourself. Okay, here we go.
我现在开门，好吗？开始了，好，开始了。 I'm opening the door now, okay?
Here we go. All right, here we go.
阿克塞尔！ Axel
别动！
迈克，你去了哪里？
Hey, Mikey.Where've you been?
什么事，扎克？ What's up, Zack?
- 你拿著什么？迈克-这是什么？你要洗的衣服？
- What have you got there, Mike?.- Here. What is this, your laundry?
我向基督发誓，扎克，我打算把它们拿回去 I swear to Christ,
Zack, I was gonna bring 'em back.
你迷路了？ - You get lost?
不是，我来看我的朋友，我有这些…
No. I came here to see my friend. I had 'em with me.
我想… I figured, you know...
- 你干什么？-我还能怎么办，迈克？ What're you doin'?.What
am I supposed to do here, Mikey?
那里有满满一大箱这东西，我拿了两叠 我不以为有人会想起它们。 There was a whole box full of those things.
I took a couple of'em. I didn't think anybody was gonna miss 'em.
我以为拿它们…
I figured I'd take 'em...
- 闭嘴-对不起，对不起 -现在闭嘴
- Shut up.- I'm sorry.I'm sorry.- Now shut up.
- 求求你 -闭嘴，迈克
- Man, please.- Shut up, Mikey.
我发誓… I swear...
我发誓，如果你再出现在那里… I swear, if you ever
show your face out there again...
-不会的，我发誓 -我是说，无论何时 -不会的，-无论何时，
- I won't man, I swear.- I won't. - I mean, ever... Ever.
我向你保证，伙计，对不起，我神经错乱了，我很抱歉。 I promise you, man.
I'm sorry.I fucked up. I'm sorry.
- 好的，无论何时 -对不起
- Okay. Ever. All right.- I'm sorry.
阿克塞尔！我认为我告诉过你了去医院 Axel，I thought I
told you to go to the hospital.
检查一下你头部的肿块。 -这不是要求，阿克塞尔。 -我的头没事 -Get that bump on your head checked.
It's not a request, Axel. -My head is all right.
老板…可否跟你谈一会？ - Make any statements to anyone?
- Boss?.Can I talk to you for a minute?
我听说你会派兰德办这宗案子，就咱俩来说，那家伙不了解情况。 I heard a rumor you're gonna use Rand on this case.
Between the two of us, the guy doesn't know the time of day.
你现在别烦我了 -这是他12年来第一次离开他的桌子 Don't mess with me now.
This is the first time he's left his desk in 12 years.
至少他做了12年
At least he's had 12 years.
不管怎样，这是谋杀案，属兰德负责。现在去医院吧。 Anyway, it's a homicide case,
and it belongs to Rand. Now go to the hospital.
-我打听一下你介意吗？ -不要做这该死的事。 - Do you mind if I ask around a little?
- Don't do a damn thing.
那是兰德的案子，你个蠢货现在的处境很危险 -我们在这儿谈的是我的一个朋友！ It's Rand's case. Your ass is
skating on thin ice as it is. -We're talking abouta friend of mine here!
是的，没错 Yes, we are, aren't we?
我们分析一下这件事。第一，一个无赖朋友 Let's take a close look at that.
One, a hoodlum friend.
第二，职业杀手行凶
Two, a professional hit.
第三，在一个警察的寓所，这整件事臭名远扬。 Three, in a cop's
apartment.This whole thing stinks to high heaven.
你怎么知道是职业杀手做的？
How do you know it was a professional hit?
我可不是刚从棉花地来到城市 I didn't just walk
into town from the cotton fields.
杀你朋友的人并不担心你个小窄屁股， Whoever killed your friend
wasn't worried about your little narrow ass.
否则你早就躺在他身边进灵车了。 If they were, you'd be
lyin' beside him in that meat wagon.
不要做这该死的事，别插手。 Just don't do a damn thing.
Stay outta this.
我还有一些假期，我想现在用我的假期。
I got some vacation time comin' to me. I wanna take my vacation now.
离这宗案子远点儿。 -我只是感到我需要一个小假期，就是这样。 Stay away from this case.
I just feel I need a little vacation. That's all.
好吧，你去完医院就放假了，-谢谢。 All right, as soon as you're finished
at the hospital, you're on vacation. Thank you.
但若你想插手这宗案件…
But if you decide to butt into this case...
那你以后都放长假了 it'll be the longest
vacation you ever heard of.
（比佛利山）
（比佛利山饭店）
（罗迪欧大道 卡地亚）
（路易威登） （妮娜丽兹 巴黎）
（凡迪 罗马）
（比佛利山劳斯莱斯公司）
今天入住吗，先生？
Checkin' in today, sir?
那要看情况, 这间饭店贵不贵？ 在比佛利山不算贵, 我给你拿行李好吗？ - Depends. This hotel real expensive?
Not for Beverly Hills.Can I get your bags for you?
好的，前座那个袋子
Yeah, that's my bag in the front seat.
抱歉，先生, 我们今晚的房间订满了 I'm sorry, sir.
We have nothing available tonight.
我建议你下次预前一周打电话来订房间 May I suggest that next time
you call for a reservation a week in advance.
谢谢 Thank you.
-你好 -有些人很难应付 - Hi.
- Nerve of some people, huh?
-有何效劳？ -阿克塞尔福里订了房间 - May I help you?
- Yes, a reservation for Axel Foley.
让我看看 Well, let's see.
对不起，没有这个登记 I'm sorry, I don't
see anything under that name.
看看滚石杂志的阿克塞尔福里，该是这个了 Oh, check Rolling Stone
magazine's Axel Foley. That's what it is.
好的…没有滚石杂志，没有阿克塞尔福里，对不起 No. No Rolling
Stone.No Axel Foley. I'm sorry, sir.
你们可能把预订的房间弄错了 That's all right. You
probably made some mistake in reservations.
干脆给我另一间房吧
Why don't you just give me another room?
对不起，先生，现在没有房间了 I'm sorry, sir, but
there are no rooms available.
你不认为我知道这儿发生了什么吗，小姐？你以为我是谁？ Don't you think I realize
what's going on here, miss?.Who do you think I am?
你不认为我知道如果我是个城外来的名人… Don't you think I know
if I was some hotshot from out of town...
你们弄错了预订，我也会马上得到房间，我现在就在楼上放松了 and you made a reservation mistake... I'd
be the first one to get a room, and I'd be upstairs relaxing right now.
我不是名人，只是滚石的小记者 I'm not a hotshot from out of town.
I'm a small reporter from Rolling Stone...
来这里做麦克杰克逊的独家采访，报导会刊登在全国各大杂志 in town to do an exclusive interview with Michael Jackson...
that's gonna be picked up by every major magazine in the country.
我想把那篇报导叫做，麦克杰克逊在世界之颠 I was gonna call the article
"Michael Jackson Is Sitting On Top OfThe World."
现在我会叫它做，麦克杰克逊可以登上世界之颠 But now I think I might as well just
call it..."Michael Jackson Can Sit On Top Of The World...
但却不能入住比佛利棕榈饭店，因为那里不准黑人入住 Just As Long As He Doesn't Sit In The
Beverly Palm Hotel... Because There's No Niggers Allowed In There."
对不起，先生，我们有一间房临时取消 Excuse me, sir, it seems
we do have a last-minute cancellation.
有一个房间
There is a room available.
是间套房，但只收你单人房的价钱 It's a suite... but I'll
only charge you the single-room rate.
谢谢你，抱歉我发脾气，可能是时差问题，我很累了，价钱多少？ Thank you. I'm sorry I got upset.lt's probably jet lag.
I'm very tired. - I understand. - What's the rate anyway?
235块一晚，先生
That'll be $235 a night, sir.
好… - Fine, fine.
- 1035号房间 -谢谢你
- That'll be suite 1035.- Thank you very much.
- 是的，先生。 -谢谢你
- Yes, sir. - Thank you. - Here you go.
要是麦可找我 告诉他我的房间号码 If Michael
calls, tell him what room I'm in.
当然，先生。 Of course, sir.
-你今天好吗？ -你好
- How you are doing today? - Hi.
我很好，我叫瑟奇，有何效劳？ I am fine. My name
is Serge.How can I help you?
我想找珍妮桑玛斯小姐
Yeah, I'm looking for Miss Jenny Summers.
这里很忙，贵姓？ She's very busy today.
Maybe you can give me your name.
- 我叫阿克塞尔福里 -有何贵干？ - My name is Axel Foley.
- And what it's "portaining"?
我不明白你说什么。 -贵干…即是关于… I didn't understand what you said.
Portaining... What it's meaning, regarding?
关于什么事？我是她的老朋友 Oh, what's it regarding?
I'm an old acquaintance of hers.
唐尼 Donny.
等一会 One moment.
唐尼，告诉桑玛斯小姐 阿梅法雷来了… Donny, run and tell Miss
Summers that Mr. Achmed Foley to see her.
- 不，是阿克塞尔福里 -阿梅尔…阿维尔…
- No, Axel Foley. - Achmel? Achwel?
阿克塞尔 -福里，是老朋友 Foley's here to see her.
He's an old acquaintance.
唐尼，把这儿盖好，别像露胸的狗一样去蹭顾客， - Donny, this is... Cover this up. Like
a breast of a dog to scrub for the customer. - I'm sorry.
-不是性感，是野性 -完全不性感 - It's not sexy. It's animal.
- It's not sexy at all.
你要饮品吗？酒、鸡尾酒、浓咖啡？ May I offer you something to drink?
A wine, a cocktail, espresso?
不用了，谢谢 No, I'm fine, thank you.
我自己做的，有柠檬汁的，你该试试 I make it myself back there
with a lemon twist. It's good. Try it.
不用了 No, I'm fine.
你欣赏这件作品 -是，我想知道它卖多少钱？ I see you look at this piece. Yeah,
I was wondering how much something like this went for.
-十三万 -把这见鬼的东西扔出去 - $130,000.
- Get the fuck outta here.
不，我不能，它是严肃的，因为它是一件很重要的作品 No, I cannot. It's
serious because it's a very important piece.
-你卖出过这其中的一个吗？ -昨天我卖给了一位收藏家。 - Have you ever sold one of these?
- I sell it yesterday to a collector.
-开他妈的玩笑 -不，真的，我亲自卖出的 - Get the fuck outta here.
- No, I'm serious. I sell it myself.
阿克塞尔福里，你到底来这儿干什么？ Axel Foley,
what on earth are you doing here?
- 你好吗？ -我很好，等一会，我下来 - How you doin'?
- I'm fine. Hold a second. I'll be down.
很好，失陪，瑟奇
Great. Excuse me, Serge.
- 你来干什么？ -你好吗？
- What are you doing here? - How you doing?
看到你真好，我也一样 - Oh, God, it's good to see you.
Same here.
- 最近过的好吗？-我很好-看看你 - How've you been?
- I've been all right. Look at you.
- 你喜欢吗？-喜欢，很好吗？你老了-去你的
- You like?.- Yeah.- Is it good?.- You gettin' old. Fuck you.
- 这是什么？-八字胡
- What is this? - Moustache.
-乳臭未干的小伙子 -不是，现在是男子汉了 - Peach fuzz.
- Naw, that's man style now.
有没有地方让我们谈谈？ You have some place
where we can talk real quick?
有的，那边，来 -很好
Well, yeah. Over there.- Great.- Come on.
- 我不相信你变胖了 -是的，我胖了
- I can't believe how you've filled out.- I've filled out.
不过很好看，坐下
No, it looks good though. Sit down.
我想谈谈迈克 -他又惹上麻烦了？ I wanna talk to you about Mikey.
Is he in trouble again?
他死了 He's dead.
什么？ 他死了。-他来到底特律，有人把他杀了 What?.He's dead. He
came to Detroit, and somebody killed him.
我不能相信 I don't believe it.
我现在不行，我很快上来 Look, I can't right now.
I'll be up in a second.
迈克提过你帮他找到一份工作 Mikey mentioned
that you helped him get a job.
是的，拥有这个画廊的家伙给我面子雇用了他 Yeah. The guy who owns
this gallery hired him as a favor to me.
这傢伙是谁？ Who's this guy?
他名叫维多麦特兰
His name is Victor Maitland.
他在画廊的仓库为维多工作 He was working for
Victor at the gallery's warehouse.
我现在不能谈，我要到楼上去 Look, Axel, I can't
talk right now.I have to go upstairs.
平静下来，我稍后找你，我们见面再谈吧 That's cool. I'll call you
later on and we'll get together and talk.
好吗？-当然。 - Okay?.- Sure.
乖一点 Be good.
你好 噢，你好 Hi，Hi
给维多麦特兰送来的 -我会把它拿到楼上给他 I have a delivery for Victor Maitland.
I'll take it right upstairs to him.
也许我该亲手交给他
Maybe I should give it to him myself.
货物该放在我桌子上，是，但这是紧急的 -他一定要收妥-我要亲自上去 - Deliveries are to be left on my desk.
Yeah, but he has to get these flowers. It's imperative. I'm going up myself.
你不应该上去
You're not supposed to go up.
送花是我的生命，我要亲自去，谢谢。 Yeah, but floral delivery is my life.
I have to take it up. Thank you.
-谁让你进来的？ -我自己 - Who let you in here?
- I let myself in.
你好吗？我有一些关于迈克坦丁诺的问题 How you doin'?.I have to
askyou some questions about Michael Tandino.
亲爱的，稍后再谈吧
Speak to you later, darling.
我能问问你对坦丁诺先生有何兴趣？ And, what, may I
ask, is your interest in Mr. Tandino?
他是我的好友，两天前他到底特律探望我 He was my best friend. He
came to see me in Detroit a couple of days ago.
他抵达不久后就被人杀死了 Couple of hours after
he got there, someone killed him.
我的天，真可怕
Oh, my God. That's terrible.
糟透了 It's fucked up.
那么…你想知道什么？ -他替你工作，是吗？ And? What do you wish to know?
He worked for you, didn't he?
是的，天！
Yes, yes, he did.Good gracious.
我很难过，你可要坐下来？我能给你点什么吗？ I'm really sorry to hear this.
Would you like to sit down?.Can I get you anything?
不用了 这件事是怎么会发生？ I'm all right.
Well, how on earth did this happen?
底特律是个很暴力的城市，对吗？
Detroit is a very violent city, isn't it?
是的 我真的希望警方能有些聪明的领导， Yeah, it is. I do hope the
police have procured some intelligent leads.
迈克到底替你做什么？
Exactly what was it Mikey did for you here?
抱歉，我听不清楚你的名字 -我姓福里 I'm sorry. I didn't
catch your name. -My name is Foley.
对不起，福里先生，原谅我有点无礼… Excuse me, Mr. Foley,
if I appear a little rude...
但听来这该是底特律当局的事 but this sounds like
something for the authorities in Detroit.
所以，请你原谅我，我要继续工作了 So, if you'll forgive
me, I really must get back to work.
我只是想知道麦克做的是什么工作， -送福里先生出去 All I want to know is what
kind of work Mikey did. Please show Mr. Foley to the door.
- 他妈的放开我 -放松点
- Get the fuck off me. - Hey, take it easy.
放开我，伙计，放开我
Get off me, man. Get off me.
他妈的放开我，走开
Get the fuck off me. Get off.
他妈的放开我，伙计，放开我
Get the fuck off me, man. Get off me.
他妈的放开我，你们以为我闹著玩？伙计？嘿，操别人去吧。 Get the fuck off me.-You think
I'm playin' games, man? Hey. Fuck with somebody else.
嘿！ Hey!
这他妈的是怎么回事？
What the fuck is this shit?
你们看到吗？我可以描述他们的长相 Did you see that shit?
I can describe all of'em.
请到车那边去，把双手放在车盖上 Please move to the side of the car.
Put your hands on the hood.
你们想怎样？-先生，你听到他说的了，请照他说的做 Why? What's with you guys?
You heard what he said, sir. Do it right now, please.
这是什么狗屁事？等一下 What kind of shit is this?
Hold up. Wait a second.
你们俩家伙要逮捕我，因为我被人抛出他妈的窗外吗？ You guys are arrestin'
me for gettin' thrown out of a window?
我被人抛出窗外！伙计。-搭档，他有枪！ I got thrown
out of a window, man. Gun, partner.
先生，你被拘捕了
Sir, you are under arrest.
你有权保持緘默… You have the right to remain silent. Anything you
say can and will be used against you in a court of law.
你有权聘请律师… You have the right to have an
attorney present during questioning.
我明白那些权利，我知道这是废话，我被人抛出他妈的窗外 Yeah, I understand. I understand the rights.
I know this is bullshit. I got thrown out of a window.
- 请上车，先生。 -告诉我，罪名是什么？ - Please, get in the car, sir.
- Tell me... what's the charge?
藏有枪械，扰乱治安 Possession of a concealed
weapon, disturbing the peace.
扰乱治安? 我被人抛出窗外！ Disturbing the peace?
I got thrown out of a window.
从车里被扔出来是什么罪名, 乱过马路吗？混帐！ What's the charge for gettin' pushed
out of a movin' car, huh?.Jaywalking? This is bullshit.
这是我坐过最干净和最舒适的警车 This is the cleanest and nicest
police car I've ever been in in my life.
这东西比我的公寓还要好
This thing's nicer than my apartment.
如果看到电影明星，你们可否指给我看？ Officers, if we see any
movie stars, could you point them out to me?
- 我从没看过 -说够了，伙计。
- I never seen no shit like that.- That's enough talkin', pal.
好的，没问题 Okay, that's cool.
很漂亮 This is nice.
是时候了，我以为你忘记我了， It's about time. I thought
you guys forgot I was down here.
我肚子很饿，我从没见过牢房里有电话，我能待会儿吗？因为我叫了披萨 I was gettin' hungry. I never been in no cell
that had a phone in it. Could I stay for a while, 'cause I ordered some pizza?
留给别人吃吧 Somebody'll eat it.
请到那边坐下
Have a seat right over there, please.
我是塔格特队长，这是我搭档罗斯伍德探员 I'm Sergeant Taggart,
and this is my partner, Detective Rosewood.
你们经常这样对待城外来的访客吗？ You always treat
visitors from out of town like this?
为何你被拘捕时不表明你是警察？ Why didn't you identify yourself
as a police officer when you were arrested?
因为我当时正处理自己的事
'Cause I was mindin' my own business.
为何你们他妈的要拘捕一个被抛出窗外的人？ Where the fuck you get off
arresting me for being thrown out a window?
有六个证人说你在那里捣乱，然后跳出窗口 We have six witnesses that say you broke in,
started tearin' up the place... then jumped out the window.
你竟然相信？你们他妈的是警察还是看门的？ You guys believe that?
Are you cops or doormen?
我们会更相信一个本地显赫的商人… We're more likely to
believe an important local businessman...
多过相信一个口出恶言的外来混蛋
than a foulmouthed out-of-town jerk.
口出恶言？去你的
Foulmouthed?.Fuck you, man.
你小心说话 -你别用什么狗屁吓唬我…你想吵架吗？ - Sarge. - Watch your mouth. Don't
square off on me with some bullshit. You wanna start some static?
- 别推我 -去你的
- Don't push me. - Fuckyou, man.
塔格特！ Taggart!
是，长官 -过来
Yes, sir. -Come here.
先生…抱歉我打你，我没什么借口 Sir... I apologize
for striking you. I have no excuse.
算了吧 Forget about it.
福里探员，我是比佛利山警察局的博戈米尔探长 Detective Foley, I'm Lieutenant
Bogomil of the Beverly Hills Police Department.
你可想起诉塔格特队长？ Do you wish to file
charges against Sergeant Taggart?
这是某种笑话，对吧？
This is some kind of joke, right?
你可想起诉这探员袭击你？ 在我们那儿，警察不会起诉警察。 Do you wish to file chargesagainst this officer for assault?
Look, where I'm from, cops don't file charges against other cops.
我不想那么做 I don't want to do that.
在比佛利山我们是严格依规矩办事 Well, in Beverly
Hills, we go strictly by the book.
你为何到来时不通知我们？ Now why didn't you
inform us when you came to town?
我在放假 -为何你在麦特兰的办公室？ I'm on vacation. If you're on vacation,
what business did you have with Victor Maitland?
我要上厕所，我经过那儿，那里看来很干净，我就停下来了。 I had to go to the bathroom.
I was walkin' by. It looked clean. I stopped.
你常带著配枪放假吗？ -不知道，我从没放过假 You always take your gun on vacation?
I don't know. I never been on vacation before.
不过在底特律，警察必须要一直携带枪械 But, in Detroit, cops are
required to carry a firearm at all times.
如果你要带枪，我建议你回去那里吧 If you wanna carry a
gun, I suggest you go back there.
我恨不得快点回去，如果你想知道真相。 I really can't wait to get
back there, if you wanna know the truth.
是吗？我刚跟底特律的陶德探员谈过 Is that so? I just got off
the phone with an Inspector Todd in Detroit.
你可记得这名字？
Does that name ring a bell?
他是我上司 -他说他们不大欢迎你回去， He's my boss. -He tells
me you may not be very welcome back there.
他说你是个出色的年轻干探 He says that you're
an outstanding young detective.
这使我难以相信
I find that very difficult to believe.
不过这是真的 It's true.
他还说他差点因为你违抗命令而把你开除，我相信是真的 He also says they nearly had to fire
you for insubordination. I find that very easy to believe.
你来这里干什么？
Now, what are you doing in Beverly Hills?
我在放假，我去上厕所，接下来你知道，有六个傢伙把我抛出窗外 I told you, I'm on vacation. I went to the bathroom.
The next thing I know, six guys throw me out a window.
可想听听陶德探员的口信？ -不用了 Inspector Todd gave me a message for you.
Wanna hear it? I don't think so.
他说若你在这里调查坦丁诺被杀一案，就别回来 He says if you're out here investigating
the Tandino murder... you needn't bother coming back.
他说若我们通知他你在调查这宗案子，他就停你的花费并开除你 He tells me that if we inform him you are
working on this case... he'll have you brought up on charges and fired.
最后一次，你在干什么？
Now, one last time, what are you doing?
- 我在放假 -放假
- I'm on vacation. - Vacation. Vacation.
罗斯伍德，带福里先生去法庭，让他准备保释 Rosewood, take Mr. Foley over
to the courthouse... and let him arrange for bail.
先生，跟我来吧
Would you follow me, sir?
我得告诉你们，你们真是非常有礼貌 I gotta hand it to you guys,
if anything, you are extremely polite.
塔格特的拳锋很凌厉
Pretty good punch you got there, Taggart.
请 Afteryou.
请 After you.
你们真是友善
You guys are so sweet, you know that?
谢谢你保释我出来
Thanks for bailin' me out, Jen.
如果我知道你被拘捕的原因，我就不会来了 Well, if I'd known why
you'd been arrested, I wouldn't have come.
你不是认真的吧
Oh, you don't mean that.
我不是认真的 No, I don't mean that.
如果不是维多麦特兰，我现在只会做侍者 Axel, if it wasn't for
Victor Maitland, I'd be waiting on tables.
迈克被杀那天，他来我公寓，拿著一袋德国无记名债券 It just so happens that the day Mikey got
killed, he came to my apartment... with a bag of German bearer bonds.
我相信是从凶手那里偷来的 Now I think he stole
'em from whoever had him killed.
当我提起迈克的名字，麦特兰就发疯并把我抛出去了 When I mentioned Mikey
to Maitland, he went nuts and threw me out.
阿克塞尔，你的样子真像无赖
Axel, you look like a hoodlum.
你没有预约，就拿著手枪闯入他的办公室 You go barging into his office
without an appointment. You're carrying a gun.
如果你闯入我的办公室并且我不认识你，我也会把你抛出去 If you barged into my
office, and I didn't know you, I'd throw you out.
这辆车是你的？ Is this your car?
不是，在比佛利山，我们都爱顺手牵羊 Oh, no, in Beverly Hills,
we just take whichever car's closest.
我记得你以前是开那辆破旧的蓝色雪佛兰新星 I remember you used
to drive that crappy, blue Chevy Nova.
你现在开什么车？
What are you driving now?
还是那辆破旧的蓝色雪佛兰新星
The same crappy, blue Chevy Nova.
-我研究艺术是太迟了吧？ -是的
- Think it's late for me to study art? - Yeah, I do.
阿克塞尔，你为什么要找维多？
Axel, why were you bothering Victor?
你不是认为他跟迈克的死有关吧？ You don't think he has anything
to do with Mikey getting killed, do you?
不是，我只是闲逛一下，我看他没做过什么 Oh, no, no. I was just poking around.
I don't think he did nothin'.
阿克塞尔，维多是美国顶尖艺术品商人，他做了十年了 Axel, Victor Maitland is one of the top
art dealers in the United States. He has been for ten years.
令我印象深刻 I'm impressed.
-你在往后面看什么？ -那些警察，他们在跟踪我们 What are you looking back there for?
The cops... they're following us.
什么？ What?..
Where? 哪里？
在后面，右边，米黄色福特
In the back on the right. The beige Ford.
看看这个房间，很不可思议吧
Do you believe this place?
阿克塞尔，你怎能负担得起？
Axel, how can you afford this?
他们只收我单人房的价钱 They're only
charging me a single-room rate.
你怎能负担得起？
How can you afford that?
我负担不来，但你可知道他们在浴室里有什么？ - Actually, I can't afford it.
But you know what they got inside that bathroom?
绣上这饭店缩写的小浴袍 Little robes with
little initials of the hotel on it.
我喜欢这里，我不想离开
I love this place. I can't leave this shit.
-我要偷一件，你要一个吗？ -不要
- I'm gonna steal a robe. You want one? - No, thanks.
要拖鞋吗？我也会偷 You want slippers? I'm gonna
steal some of them too. Take some of this.
对不起，等一会 Excuse me two seconds.
客房服务，我是1035号房间的福里先生 Hello, room service.
Yes, this is Mr. Axel Foley in suite 1035.
我想点宵夜餐点 Yeah, I'd like to order
something from your late supper menu.
你们把它送去停在威尔希尔道的米黄色福特 But listen, I want to deliver
it to this beige Ford that's on Wilshire.
送一客大虾沙拉三明治去，对 Send down one bay
shrimp salad sandwich. Okay? Right.
蒔萝汁蒸鮭鱼凉拌好吃吗 And is the cold poached
salmon in dill sauce tasty?
好，送一客去，还要一些甜品 Okay. Send one of those down.
And send something for dessert. Thanks.
很好，谢谢 All right, thank you.
你真是个淘气鬼，你会住多久？ You're quite a sport.
How long are you gonna stay?
直到我知道谁杀了迈克为止 I'm gonna be in town
until I find out who killed Mikey.
我很认真的考虑要去他工作的仓库调查一下 And I'm very seriously considering going down
to that warehouse... where he worked and checkin' that place out.
真的？你打算怎样进去？ Oh, really? And how
are you planning on getting in?
-先生，晚上好 -这他妈的是什么？ -宵夜，福里先生的问候 Good evening, sir.
- What the hell is that? - Late supper, compliments of Mr. Foley.
-福里？他怎知道我们在这？ -因为我让你开车 Foley? How'd he
know we were here? 'Cause I let you drive.
我要两条香蕉，多少钱？ I need a couple of bananas.
How much are they?
自助餐是12.5块，有桃子、李子、橙和香蕉 The buffet plate is $12.50.
You get peaches, plums, oranges and bananas.
我只想要两条香蕉
All I need is a couple of bananas.
嘘，走吧，拿着香蕉。
Shh. Go ahead.Take those bananas.
谢谢 Thanks.
-我不要，拿回去吧 -这个看起来很好 Forget it. I'm not eating that. Take it back.
- Certainly, sir. - This really looks great.
我能多要一些蛋黄酱？
Can I get some extra mayo?
- 当然可以 -谢谢
- Certainly, sir. - Thank you.
- 行了吗？ -行了
- Ready to go?.- Yeah.
那辆梅赛德斯出现了，你别吃了好吗？ There's the Mercedes.
Will you get rid of that stuff?
你他妈的干什么？
What the hell are you doin'?
是这里吗？ This the place?
是的，但我不知道是否该这么做 Yeah, but I'm
still not sure I should do this.
你不必做，但当你听到砸破玻璃时别惊慌 Don't do anything, but when
you hear glass breakin', don't get scared.
只是我在踢窗罢了，放心 It's just me kickin'
in the window. Sit tight.
来吧，阿克塞尔
All right. Come on, Axel.
-宝贝，怎么了？ -阿克塞尔，正经点
- What's happenin', baby? - Axel, grow up.
-有发现吗？ -咖啡渣。 - You find something?
- Coffee grounds.
-那又如何？ -可知道这东西有什么用？ So?.You know
what this stuff is used for?
人们用热水把它过滤后再饮用 Yeah, some people filter
hot water through it and drink it.
我会带这个回家, 早上用热水把它过滤后再喝 I'll take this home, filter
hot water through it and drink it in the morning.
我们干嘛要躲起来？
What are we hiding for?
可惜你昨天没来 I wanna tell ya, I wish you
would've been with me last night.
发生了什么事？ -我们回家途中去了一间酒吧喝了几杯。 What happened? I stopped
at a joint on the way home to have a couple of drinks.
-哪一间？ -一间本地的酒吧 - Which one?
- One of the local joints.
有个傢伙走进来，坐在附近 Some guy comes in,
sits down a couple of stools away.
他有一只眼睛这样的眨著 He's got... one of
them eyes that's goin' like this.
我不知道他是否在挑逗我 I didn't know if he was
tryin'to put the make on me or what.
我想今晚带你去 So I thought I'd
take you over there tonight.
让他挑逗你，然后我揍他一顿 Let him have a little
shot at you before I tore his head off.
我们走吧，我要离开这里
Let's go. I wanna get out of here.
-能不能别管我 -来吧 Why don't you
get off my back? Come on.
行了 I got it.
-这是什么回事？ -我稍后会告诉你 - What the hell's going on?
- I'll tell you later. Come on.
快点，快点 - Hurry up. - Hurry up.
把钥匙交给我，我要跟踪他 -你以前开过梅赛德斯没有？ -汽车罢了，我每天开我的车 - Gimme the key. I'm gonna follow 'em.- You
ever driven a Mercedes before? No, but a car is a car.I drive my car every day.
我来开吧，我看过你的车
I'm driving. I've seen your car.
噢，靠，那真令人沮丧。
Oh, shit. That's cold.
香蕉在排气管里？你们怎会没发觉有人把香蕉塞进排气管 A banana in your tailpipe? How could
you not notice a man sticking a banana in your tailpipe?
-他令我们分心 -怎样？ - Well, he distracted us, sir.
- And how'd he do that?
他给我们送来一客宵夜，那个服务生走过来… He sent us a late
supper, sir.See, this waiter comes over...
比利，他明白的
Billy, he gets the point.
宵夜？你们吃了什么？ A late supper. And
what did you have, Rosewood?
一客大虾沙拉三明治 I think it was a
shrimp salad sandwich, sir.
-大虾沙拉三明治？ -是的
- A shrimp salad sandwich. - Yes, sir.
我要你们俩回饭店里等福里露面 I want you two to go back to
the hotel and wait for Foley to show up.
要是你们再让他走丢，就别回来，知道吗？ And if you lose him
again, don't bother calling in. You got that?
- 知道 -知道
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
一客宵夜 A late supper.
比利，我们有样东西送给你
We've got something for you, Billy.
一个防香蕉面具
An anti-banana disguise.
-可能有用 -额外的保护措施，比利 - It may come in handy.
- A little extra protection, Billy.
很有趣 Very funny.
来吧，比利，我们走吧
Come on, Billy. Let's go.
你开车回家去吧
Take the car and go home.
-那你呢？ -我要看看这是什么地方
- Well, what about you? I wanna find out what this place is.
我可以告诉你，它是个保税仓库 I can tell you that.
It's a bonded warehouse.
他们把我们的进口货物存放在这里，等候通关。 They hold our foreign
shipments here until they clear customs.
我去查看一下，开车回家去，好吗？ I'm gonna check it
out.Just take the car and go home, okay?
该死，阿克塞尔 - Damn it, Axel.
- 我不会再保释你的 - 回家去
- I'm not gonna bail you out again. - Go home.
（外国货品入境区）
（海关保税关栈）
你好吗？请过来一会 How ya doin'? Could you
come here for a second, please?
-有火柴吗？ -这里不准抽烟 - Hi. Do you have a match?
- There's no smokin' in here.
我不是要抽烟 我出去后才抽，谢谢 I'm not gonna smoke now.
I'm gonna smoke when I go outside.
-你是这里的主管吗？ -他在办公室 - Is your supervisor here?
- Yeah, he's in the office.
-请叫他出来 -有什么问题？ - Can you get him for me?
- What's the problem?
-你是保安员？ -是的
- Are you security here? - Yeah.
那你就是该死的问题，叫你的主管出来，快点 Then you're the fuckin' problem.
Go get your supervisor, please. Now.
现在！ 好的 - Now! - Okay.
他还没回来 He didn't come back yet.
我们怎么办？ Well, what do we do now?
我们等著 We wait.
Okay. 好的
-有什么事？ -你是主管吗？ - Can I help you?
- Are you the supervisor here?
-是的，你是谁？ -拉佛蒂探员，美国海关 - Yes. Who are you?
- Inspector Rafferty, U.S. Customs.
所有这些货物已经通关了吗？ -没有，这里是保税区。 Has all this stuff passed
through customs already? No, this is the bonded area.
那么告诉我，一个像我这样打扮的黑人… Tell me something.
How can a black man, dressed like me,
怎么可以长驱直入你的仓库, 走进保税区来闲逛却没有任何人问我任何问题？ just march into your warehouse... walk into the
bonded area and start poking around... without anyone askin' me any questions whatsoever?
-我不知道 -正是我要的答案 - Well, I don't know.
- That's the answer I was lookin' for.
告诉我你的编号，有人会失业了 Why don't you guys just give me your I.D.
numbers?.'cause some guy gonna lose their job
-他竟然给我一支火柴 -你给了他一支火柴？ - This guy gave me a match.
- You gave him a match?
听著，我在国内四处作保安检查 Listen to me. I do
security checks all over the nation...
除了克利夫兰，这里的保安是全国最糟 and with the exception of Cleveland...
this place has the worst security in the nation.
告诉你们的太太，我们今晚会通宵留在这里 I suggest you guys call your
wives, 'cause we're gonna be here all night.
我们要检查所有箱子的背景，从这一箱开始 We're gonna check the background of every
crate in this section... starting with this one right here.
这里说美国人平均到了五十岁 You know it says here that
by the time the average American is 50...
他的肠里就有五磅未消化的红肉 he's got five pounds
of undigested red meat in his bowels.
你干嘛要告诉我？
Why are you telling me this?
你为何认为我对这个有兴趣？ What makes you think I
have any interest in that at all?
你吃很多红肉
Well, you eat a lot of red meat.
这位探员需要全部的空运提单资料… Now, the inspector needs
information on those airway bill numbers.
还有全部的提货单 All the manifests too.
他还要全部运往同一目的地的货物记录 He needs the records of
shipments due into the same destination.
-这是什么回事？ -只管做吧
- What's this all about? - Just do it.
你有没有被授权这样做的？
You got some kind of warrant for this?
先生，你真是多嘴，你是否有事隐瞒著我？ You have a very big mouth, sir. Are
you hiding something from me? Is that what you're doing?
外面那辆保时捷是你的吧？ I bet that's your
Porsche parked outside, isn't it?
你可想我找国税局爬上你他妈的屁股用显微镜仔细的查一下？ Would you like for me to
have the IRS crawl up your ass with a microscope?
我看过他们那么做，很难看的 'Cause they'll do it. I've
seen 'em do it. It's not a pretty sight.
我可以在十五分钟内叫二十五名探员到来 I want you to know something.I want you all to
know something. I can have 25 agents down here in 15 minutes...
冲进来搜查你们的仓库，抢走你们的票据... to march in here,
snatch your bond from underneath you...
若你们不合作就要永远停业 -明白吗？ and you'll be out of business
for good if I don't get cooperation, understood?
别生气，探员，-我们会给你所需的一切，是吗，伙计们？ Don't get upset, Inspector.
We'll give you everything you need, right, guys?
-你所需的一切 -那辆保时捷不是我的 - Everything you need.
- That's not my Porsche, sir.
那你可以放心，你们以为我是笨蛋吗？ You ain't got nothin'to worry about then. I don't
know what you think I am, take me for some kind of fool. Hurry.
我发觉你最近喝很多咖啡 You know, I noticed you've
been drinking a lot of coffee lately.
所以你很难放松 Well, I think that's why
you have a hard time relaxing.
天！你差点让我发心脏病 Jesus Christ.- You
almost gave me a heart attack.
-你们这么晚在这里干嘛？ -你是个自大的婊子养的混蛋，
- What are you doing here so late? You're a cocky son of a bitch, aren't you?
若你还在生那香蕉的气，对不起，我只是需要点私人时间 Look, if you're still mad about the
banana thing, I'm sorry. I just needed a little time to myself.
真希望看到车子故障时你们脸上的表情 I wish I would've saw the
expression on your face when your car conked out.
很有趣, 探长扣了我们两天的薪水 Yeah, very funny.The
lieutenant docked us two days' pay.
开玩笑？ Get outta here.
-他不是说笑的 -不是 - He's not kidding.
- No, he's not kidding.
顺便说一下，谢谢你的三明治
By the way, thanks for the sandwich.
他在开玩笑，
He meant it as a joke, Billy.
像那条香蕉一样。 等等，我是警察，我明白监视行动的苦况 - Like the bananas.
Wait a minute. I'm a fellow police officer. I know what it's like to be on a stakeout.
那些食物是我的心意 -胡说！ When I sent that food
down, that was from the heart. Bullshit.
为何我们总要吵架？我们都是警察，该一起合作 Why are we always arguin'?.All
three of us are cops. We should be working together.
我们今天辛苦了
We all had a very rough day today.
怎么样，我们去喝杯酒，言归于好并且交个朋友，好吗？ What do you say, we all go get
somethin' to drink... and make up and be friends, huh?
休想 Forget it.
没关系，我会去喝酒，你们想喝就跟著我吧 Okay, fuck it.
I'm gonna get something to drink.
但我甩掉过你们，我可以再做一次 You can try to follow me if you want, but I
lost y'all once today... which means I can do this shit again.
去喝一杯吧，我们交个朋友 Why don't you say we get something
to drink together. Let's be friends.
-我们值班时不喝酒 -好，没问题 - We don't drink on duty.
- Okay, fine, all right.
但我找到一个好地方， But listen to me.
I found the perfect place.
我今天在路上看到的，很适合你们的，它很保守，你们会喜欢它的， I saw it on the way over here today.lt's perfect
for you guys. You can go. It's very conservative. You guys'll love it.
放心，那儿很好，相信我吧
Don't worry, it's nice. Trust me.
That's right, pleased to meet you
I still won't tell you my name.
Don't you believe in mystery
-你们好，要喝点什么？ -享受一下…威士忌加苏打 - Don't you wanna play my game.
- Hi. Can I get you something? Yes. I'm having a great time. Can I have a Scotch and soda?
还有…你们喝什么？给他们淡啤酒 And the brothers... what
y'all want?.Lite beers for the fellas.
两杯苏打水 Two club sodas.
你们这个值班的废话，笑死我了 You guys crack
me up with this on-duty shit.
比利，要是你的那话儿硬了，不用尴尬 You don't have to be
embarrassed if your dick gets hard.
你的那话儿该变硬的，目的就是这样 It's supposed to get hard.
See? That's the whole object of this.
塔格特的那话儿是硬的，但他不会说的，他是老大 Taggart's dick gets hard,
but he won't let you know 'cause he's the boss.
老大的那话儿要保持柔软，我没在值班，我的可以变硬 The boss' dick got to stay
limp, right?.I ain't on duty, so mine can be hard.
塔格特，看 Hey, Taggart, look.
看看这个，我在麦特兰的仓库找到的 Check that out. I
found that at Maitland's warehouse.
-比利！把这个给她 -不 Billy. Bill, here.
Give her this. Really, no,
塞入她裤边，她会发疯的 stuff that inside her
little thing, and she'll go nuts.
对不起 Excuse me.
Billy 比利
-你认为是什么？ -咖啡渣 - What do you think?
- Coffee grounds.
-对
-那又如何？
- Yeah.
- So?
你们什么都不知道，是吧？ You guys don't know
nothin' about nothin', do you?
你们戴著警章和手枪便得工作 You got your badges and
guns, and you're on the job, right?
别弄错饮品，我喝苏打水会吐 Make sure we get the right drinks.
If I drink club soda, I'll throw up.
谢谢你 Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
Tonight, I'm living in a fantasy
in my own little nasty world.
Tonight, did you wanna come with
me Do you think I'm a nasty girl
她喜欢你呢 I think she likes you.
- 真的？ - 我肯定是 - Think so?
- There's no doubt in my mind.
塔格特，看那个穿黑色大衣的傢伙 Taggart, see that
guy over there in the black coat?
黑色大衣？ Black jacket.
-对 现在是六月，穿黑色皮大衣不热吗？ - Yeah?
- It's June. Don't you think it's hot for a long, black leather coat?
-对，有点热 -是的
- Yeah, a little bit. - Yeah.
看看他的搭档，他们刚进来 Look at his partner over
there.They just came in together.
快要发生事情了
Something's gettin' ready to go down.
为什么你不去查一下那个傢伙 Why don't you go over
there and cover that guy for me?
-什么事？ 我去看看酒吧那混蛋，比利不会让我胡来 - What's going on?
- I'll check out the asshole at the bar.Billy's gonna make sure that I behave.
有谁告诉我有什么事？
Somebody tell me what's going on.
这次不是说笑 No bullshit this time.
比利，别走开 Just sit tight, Billy.
That'll work.
That's right I can't control it.
Tonight I can no longer hold it.
Get it up, get it up I can't wait anymore
菲利浦！ Philip!
老兄，怎么了？菲尔
Hey, man, what's happenin', Phil?
我知道是你，他说你不再来了，但我说： 是菲利浦 I knew that was you.He told me it
wasn't, that you don't come here no more. But I said, it's him.
-走开 -是菲利浦 - Get outta here.
- It is Philip. I told you it's Philip, you liar.
-给我亲一下 -我叫你滚开！ Gimme a kiss.
I said, get the hell away.
全部人别动！ Everybody, freeze!
转过身去… Turn around. Turn around.
-菲尔！ -把手放在桌上！ - Phil.
- Get the hands on the table.
菲尔！什么事？干嘛这么凶？-菲尔？ Phil! What's wrong,
man?.What's all the hostility, Phil?
-退后 -你拿这支枪搞什么？ - Get back.
- What you doin' with this gun?
我说过了退后 你变了 - I told you to get back.
- You changed, man.
退后，否则我把你他妈的轰掉 Get back. If you don't,
I'll blow your fuckin' brains out.
警察，别动 Police. Move,
and I'll kill you.
别动！转过身去！ Don't move! Turn over!
干得好，你是个出色的警察，知道吗？ Way to go, Rosewood.
You're some kind of cop, you know that?
抱歉骚扰了大家，一切受到控制了 Sorry for the disturbance,
folks.Everything's under control.
塔格特 Taggart
你可否解释为何你和罗斯伍德在值班时间… Would you mind explaining
to me why you two were in a strip bar...
出现在我们警局以外的一间脱衣舞酒吧？ out of our jurisdiction,
when you were still on duty?
长官，在你责罚这两位探员前你该知道一件事 Sir, before you chastise
these two, there's something you should know.
他们所以在脱衣舞酒吧里是因为他们在跟踪我 The only reason they were at a strip bar...
is because they were tailing me, and I went to this place.
他们在外面怀疑我在干什么 These two officers were sitting
outside, wondering what I was doing.
我在里面玩著，我很喜欢那些玩意 I was in having a good time.
I'm into things like that.
他们在外面等著，他们之所以走了进去… Anyway, these guys waited
outside, and the only reason they came in...
是因为他们看见两个外衣有异物凸出的可疑人物进去 was because they saw two suspicious-looking gentlemen...
with bulges in their jackets going into the place.
原来那两个傢伙想抢劫 Well, it turns out that these
guys were gonna commit a robbery, sir.
他们静候他们下手，把一宗罪案瓦解了 These men watched them, waited for them
to make their move... and then they foiled the crime.
我不知道发生什么事，我当时在看表演 I did not know what was going on.
I was watchin' the show, havin' fun.
我仍然很惊慌，他们一定是有第六感 I'm still freaked out by it.
They must have a sixth sense.
我不知道你怎么教导他们，但他们不是普通的警察 I don't know what you teach
these guys, but they're not just regular cops.
他们是超级警察，他们身上只是欠了一件斗蓬 Okay? They're super cops. And
the only thing missing on these guys are capes.
是真的吗？
Is this what really happened?
不是的 No, sir.
谁能把实情告诉我？ Would someone like to
tell me what really happened?
福里邀请我们去这间酒吧，我们接受了 Well... Foley invited
us to this bar, and we accepted.
-我们要了苏打水 -对
- We ordered club sodas, sir. - Right.
我们在那里时…
And while we were there...
福里察觉那两个可疑人物，正在虎视眈眈 Foley observed the
two suspects casing the establishment.
我们还不知道发生什么事，他已把其中一人的手枪拿下了 And before we knew what
was going on, he'd already disarmed one of'em.
这次拘捕该归功于福里探员 Detective Foley deserves
all the credit for the arrest, sir.
福里探员，我们感谢你的协助 Detective Foley...
we appreciate your assistance...
但将来我宁愿你在底特律，执行法纪 but in the future, if you want to practice
law enforcement... I would prefer you did it in Detroit.
我明白，对不起
I understand, sir.I'm sorry.
但我想你们俩知道，那超级警察的说法挺管用 But before I go, I just want you
two to know something: The super-cop story was working.
知道吗？它管用的，你们却把它弄乱 Okay? It was working.You
guys just messed it up. Okay?
我还想不透你们搞什么，但这样很好 I'm trying to figure you
guys out, but I haven't yet, but it's cool.
把一个绝妙的谎话弄糟，也没问题 You fuck up a perfectly
good lie, and it's all right.
你们不用办这个案了
You guys are off the case.
佛斯特、麦凯布，你们接手，别让他跑掉
Foster. McCabe. Your turn. Don't lose him.
绝对不会 Not a chance, sir.
你们俩进来我办公室
And you two, in my office.
两位早，要咖啡和甜甜圈吗？ Good morning,
gentlemen.Some coffee and doughnuts?
-什么？ -咖啡和甜甜圈 - What?
- Coffee and doughnuts.
他来了 There he is.
两位探员早，你们是第二队？ Morning, officers.
What? Y'all the second team?
我们是第一队 - We're the first team.
- Yeah.
我们不会中香蕉塞进排气管的计 We're not gonna
fall for a banana in the tailpipe.
你们不会中香蕉塞进排气管的计？ You're not gonna
fall for the banana in the tailpipe?
兄弟，应该说得自然一点，像这样： It should be more natural,
brother.lt should flow out.Like this,
我不会中香蕉塞进排气管的计 "Look, man, I ain't
fallin'for no banana in my tailpipe!"
这样自然一点，你跟这个傢伙混得太久了 That's more natural for us.
You've been hanging out with this dude too long.
抱歉，我跟你们开玩笑罢了，我觉得很有趣，对不起 Sorry. I'm just fuckin' with ya.
That's funny to me. Sorry.
-你们想跟上我？ -没问题 So y'all gonna try
to keep up with me? No problem.
-这里不是维多麦特兰的家吗？ -我想是的
- Isn't this Victor Maitland's house? - Yeah, I think so.
我看够了，你们可要饮品？ Well, I seen enough. Y'all
want something to drink? Beer or somethin'?
我的行李箱里有些饮料，对不起
I got some stuff in the trunk.Excuse me.
你在放假，看起来却像在进行监视 For a man who claims to be on
vacation, you look like you're on a stakeout.
监视？不是，我在野餐，这里是野餐区 Stakeout?.I'm picnicking.
This is like a picnic area.
我聊得太久了，我想去到处观光了，失陪 Well, guys, I been shootin'the shit long enough.
Time for me to take in some sights. Excuse me.
他在干什么？ What's he doing?
你能把它停在个好地方吗，上次停在这里时弄成这样 Can you put this in a good spot?.All
this shit happened the last time I parked here. Thank you.
有何效劳？ May I help you?
是的，我想找维多麦特兰
Yes. I'm lookin'for Victor Maitland.
你知道俱乐部只招待会员的吧？ You realize that
this is a members-only club?
我要跟维多谈谈，是非常，非常，重要的事 But I have to talk to Victor.
It's very, very important.
维多麦特兰，你肯定？
You sure it's Victor Maitland you want?
是，维多麦特兰，灰发男士，皮肤很黑，魔羯座 The gray-haired
gentleman, very dark skin, Capricorn.
不如你把口信给我，我会交给他 Why don't you give me
the message, and I'll take it to him.
好，告诉维多，他一周前认识的拉蒙 I guess I can do that. Tell Victor
that Ramon, the fella he met about a week ago...
告诉他拉蒙去过诊所… Tell him that Ramon
went to the clinic today.
我发觉我染了…单纯性十号泡疹 I found out that I have...
herpes simplex ten.
我想维多该找医生检查一下 I think Victor should go
check himself out with his physician...
免得病情突发 to make sure everything is fine
before things start fallin' off on the man.
还是你告诉他吧
Perhaps you better tell him that.
-这最好不过了 -我也同意 You know, I think
that would be best. So do I.
你好，维多 Hi，Victor
我回来了 I'm back.
大伙儿，别胡来
Look, cous', don't even try it, okay?
你干嘛不快从这儿滚出去？ Why don't you get
the hell outta here, cous'?
他妈的离我远点儿，
Get the fuck away from me, man.
很好，维多，你可否也教他滚开坐下？ That's very good. Could you
teach him to roll over and sit and all that too?
你想怎么样？-谈一下 -我们上次可没有机会谈 -我跟你无话可说。 -好，那就全由我来说吧 - What do you want? - I want to talk to you.Last time we met I
didn't get a chance to talk to you. - I have nothing to say to you.- That's cool. I'll do all the talking.
这是个很好的地方，维克
This is a very nice place, Vic.
你好…我喜欢这里，很好
Hi. I like this. This is nice.
我很高兴你喜欢他，我得使你成为会员
Glad you like it. I must make you a member.
维多，我知道你做著很多勾当 I know that you're
into a lot of crooked shit.
我有个非常好的想法就是你杀了迈克 I have a pretty
good idea that you had Mikey killed.
当我找到证据时，我会狠狠的把你打得稀巴烂。 When I find out for
sure, I'm gonna fuck you up real bad.
是吗？听我说，我难缠的小朋友， Is that so?.Listen
to me, my tough little friend.
我不知道你从哪块石头底下爬过来的… I don't know from
under what stone you crawled...
也不知道你哪得来的关于我的这些荒谬想法 or where you get
these ridiculous ideas about me...
但很明显…
but it seems painfully obvious...
你一点也他妈的不知道你在跟谁交手 you haven't the slightest
fucking idea who you're dealing with.
我给你的忠告是…
Now, my advice to you is...
快爬回底特律你的小石头底下，在你被压扁之前，好吗？ crawl back to your little
stone in Detroit... before you get squashed, okay?
请离开这张桌子
Please step away from the table, sir.
-我要走了，维多 -再次见到你真好。 - Gotta go now, Vic.
- Nice meeting you again.
稍后见吧，维多 Catch ya later, Vic.
我巴不得快点 I can't wait.
我在某处见过你们吗？你们很面熟呢 Don't I know you guys
from someplace? You look so familiar.
福里探员，这件事越来越恼人了 Detective Foley,
this is becoming very irritating.
你为何要骚扰维多麦特兰？
Why are you bothering Victor Maitland?
我的朋友迈克坦丁诺以前替他工作 I had a friend named Michael
Tandino that used to work for Victor Maitland.
麦特兰找人杀了他，现在我无法证明，但我找到证据时你会第一个知道。 Maitland had him killed. I can't
prove that right now, but when I do, you'll be the first to know.
别管你能证明什么了，跟我说吧
Forget what you can prove.Talk to me.
好，听著，众所周知，麦特兰是个著名的艺术品商人 Everybody knows Victor
Maitland is a hotshot art dealer, okay?
但我调查过，他不单是买卖艺术品 I did some poking around.
Art's not the only thing that he deals.
我去过他的仓库，看见他们缷下一箱无记名债券 I went to his warehouse.I saw some guys
unloading a crate... that was filled with German bearer bonds.
迈克坦丁诺被杀时，恰巧身上也有这样的债券 My friend Michael had bonds like this on him...
coincidently, when he was killed in Detroit.
麦特兰投资在同一样的债券上 Just because he chooses to invest
in the same kind of bonds your friend had...
并不代表他就是杀人凶手
doesn't necessarily mean he's a killer.
他不是投资者，他是个走私贩 The man's not an investor.
He's a smuggler...
不管是债券、毒品，我看见的箱子甚至没有通关 be it bonds or drugs or whatever.
The crate that I saw didn't even pass through customs.
麦特兰收买了一些人因此他的人在海关检查前把货物弄了出来 Maitland is paying someone so his guys
can get the shipments out of customs before they get inspected.
他的手下取货以后，就把毒品或者债券拿出来 When Maitland's guys get their hands on it...
they take the drugs or the bonds out of the crates...
然后在海关发现前把它送回去 and they send it back before
customs even knows what's going on.
你目睹这个情况？
You witnessed all this?
除了毒品，但我在仓库到处都能找到咖啡渣 Everything except for the drugs...
but I found coffee grounds all over the warehouse.
咖啡渣？ -这之前你说了些事，什么意思？ Coffee grounds? You said
something about that before. What does that mean?
把毒品包装在咖啡里，气味会瞒过警犬 Drugs are sometimes packed in
coffee grounds. The scent throws off the dogs.
很好，我们现在怎么办？
Very good, Lieutenant. Now what do we do?
福里探员，我…
Look, Detective Foley...
很抱歉，我真的很想帮你，若你找到毒品就好 I'm sorry.I'd really like to
help you.lf you'd found the drugs, that's one thing.
但你唯一的证据是咖啡渣，我们便拿不到搜查令 But if your only evidence is coffee grounds...
we don't have enough to get a search warrant.
我们可以靠关系… -我们不靠关系拿搜查令的 I know how we can get around...
We don't get around search warrants in Beverly Hills.
塔格特，我要你去调查一下
Taggart.I want you to start checking this out. Yes, sir.
从洛杉矶警察局，联邦调查局和海关著手 Start with the LAPD,
the FBI and the Customs Service.
塔格特，等一下…探长，麦特兰很精明的 Wait a minute.
Maitland is much smarter than that.
若我们到处打探，他会收手，从别处取货 We snoop around, he'll close
down and get his shipments from someplace else.
- 那将会浪费很多时间。 真的？你丰富的经验，令你相信是这样吗？ - It'd be a big waste of time.
- Oh, really?.ls that what your extensive experience leads you to believe?
-我没有在警队… -长官…
- I haven't been on the force... - Sir!
该死 Shit.
-就是这个人吗？ 是的，长官
- Is this the man? - Yes, sir.
把维多麦特兰的窗撞破的先生？ Is this the gentleman who
crashed through Victor Maitland's window?
用香蕉把一辆没标志的警车弄坏的人？ Who disabled
an unmarked unit with a banana?
是的，长官 Yes, sir.
引诱塔格特和罗斯蒙特去一间脱衣舞酒吧… Who lured Taggart and
Rosemont into a gross dereliction of duty...
导致他们严重失职的人？
at a striptease establishment?
-是罗斯伍德 -是的，长官 It's Rosewood, sir.
Yes, sir.
今早在哈罗俱乐部毁了自助餐的先生是不是他？ Is this the gentleman who
ruined the buffet at the Harrow Club this morning?
是的，长官 Yes, sir.
我打赌在底特律你是你部门的光荣 I just bet you are the
pride of your department in Detroit.
探长，我想在你的办公室见你 Lieutenant, I'd
like to see you in your office.
是，长官 Yes, sir.
今早在哈罗俱乐部毁了自助餐的是不是他？ Is this the man who wrecked
the buffet at the Harrow Club this morning?
小声一点，看在上帝份上。
Lower your voice, for Christ's sake.
-他穿过墙壁也能听到？ -他可以
- Can he hear me through the wall? - Yes, he can.
罗斯伍德，送福里探员回饭店里 Rosewood, take Detective
Foley back to his hotel room...
看著他收拾行李，护送他到本市边境 watch him pack
and，escort him to the city limits.
然后你可以把枪交还给他 When you get there,
you can give him his gun back.
控告你扰乱公安的两项罪名，已经被撤消 The two charges of disturbing
the peace have been dropped against you.
但局长说，如果你回到比佛利山… But the chief says if you
return to the city of Beverly Hills...
就会重新控告你，你就会受到法律制裁 the charges will be reinstated...
and you will be prosecuted to the limit of the law.
-长官，我可否发言？ -什么？
- Sir, may I say something? - What?
-他看来有足够的线索… -你可想告诉局长？ He seems to have enough to
follow up... You want to tell that to the chief?
-不想 -那我提议你快点去 - No, sir.
- Then I suggest you get moving.
来吧，阿克塞尔 Come on.
好的，我明天看看再回复你吧 Right. Let me check on
that tomorrow and get right back to you.
谢谢 Thank you.
-你好
-维多，你好
-hi
-vic, hi
-坐下，我没有打扰你吧 -当然没有 Sit down. Hope I'm
not interrupting. Don't be silly.
珍妮，有个来自底特律的男人…他说他是迈克坦丁诺的朋友 There's a gentleman
from Detroit who says he's a friend ofTandino.
他昨天来过公司问了我一些古怪的问题 He came by the office yesterday
and asked me all sorts of odd questions.
对不起，亲爱的 Excuse me, darling.
我相信他的名字是福里, 既然你是迈克的好朋友, 我想知道或许你熟悉那个家伙 I believe his name is Foley.Since you were such a
good friend of Michael's... I was wondering if you were perhaps familiar with the fellow?
我们一同长大，他是我邻居
We grew up in the same neighborhood.
真的？你最近可有见过他？
Really? Have you seen him lately?
他昨天来过 He came in yesterday.
什么？他来过这里？ What? Came by here?
噢
还有呢？ And?
他告诉我迈克被人杀死了
He told me Mikey had been killed.
是，我知道， Yes. Yes, I know.
还有呢？ 没有了, 他离开后我就没见过他了 - And then?
That's it. He left, and I haven't seen him since.
珍妮，你可知道他住在哪里？ You wouldn't, by any
chance, know where Foley is staying?
我有些他可能有用的资料 I have some information
which just might be helpful for him.
我不知道 I have no idea.
很好 Yes.
希望我们没有太打扰到你 -没问题 Well, I hope we didn't
disturb you too much. No problem.
我们改天吃晚饭，好吗？ 那将令人愉快。 - We'll have dinner soon, yes?
- Why, that would be lovely.
保重 Take care.
比利，我看过那些提货单，他们今天会有另一批货到来 I read the manifest, all right?
They're expecting another shipment today.
-博戈米尔… -算了吧 - If Bogomil...
- Never mind Bogomil!
这是让我们破案的机会 This is a chance for me and you to
blow this case wide open. What do you say?
-但愿我可以，但我不行 -为什么？
- I wish I could, but I can't. - Why?
因为博戈米尔会杀死我
Because Bogomil would kill me.
比利 Billy.
我不能载你去画廊
I'm not driving you to the art gallery.
只消两分鐘，我的朋友，珍妮会让我们进入麦特兰的仓库 - It'll just take a few minutes.My
friend, Jenny, will let us in Maitland's warehouse.
那批货到达时我们就能当场抓到他们 We can be there when
the shipment comes in and nail 'im!
你怎么能肯定它是毒品？
How can you be sure it'll be drugs?
我有直觉，明白吗？一种比佛利山以外的破案技巧 - I got a hunch, okay?.That's a
technique by which crimes outside of Beverly Hills get solved.
你为何不向博戈米尔提及这批货？ Why didn't you
tell Bogomil about this shipment?
他做什么都依规矩办事
Bogomil does everything by the book.
我开始相信这个城市里的人都是机械人 I'm starting to think
everybody in this town is a robot.
这件事对我很重要
This thing is very personal to me.
他只叫我开车送你离城 All he asked me to
do was drive you out of town.
现在我连这件事都办不好，天
Now I'm gonna screw that up too.
比利，我爱你，我刚爱上了你
I love you.I just fell in love with you.
珍妮，你好吗？这是我的朋友，比利罗斯伍德…珍妮桑玛斯 This is my good
buddy Billy Rosewood. This is Jenny Summers.
-你好 -比利是比佛利山警察 - Billy's a Beverly Hills cop.
- How do you do?
-你好吗？ -这是瑟奇 That's Serge.
Yo, Serge.
瑟奇，可否给你的朋友来一杯咖啡？
Will you get my friend an espresso?
要不要加柠檬碎片？
You want it with a lemon twist?
-好的，如果不是很麻烦 -不麻烦，别傻 Yeah, sure, if it's no bother.
No, don't be stupid.
亚斯里，维多麦特兰今天来过这里打听你 Victor Maitland was
here asking questions about you today.
他的态度很古怪
I'm telling you he was acting real weird.
我来这儿的原因是想再去那间仓库 The reason I came down here is
'cause I want to get back inside the warehouse.
我陪你去好吗？ -你和瑟奇在画廊工作，不是警察 How about I go with you? You
work here with Serge in an art gallery. You're not a cop.
如果这件事跟迈克的死有关，我就要去看看 If this has anything to do
with Mikey getting killed, I want to check it out.
我没有时间跟你争论 I don't have time to
stand here and argue with you.
我去拿钥匙，我们在途中争论吧 Wait a second. Let me get
my keys, and we'll argue on the way.
比利，你坐在这里监视著，我叫你才可以行动 Your job's to sit out here
and observe things. I'll come out and get you.
- 为何我不能进去？
- I don't see why I can't come in.
因为你是本地的警察，没有充分的证据就是非法搜查 'Cause you're a cop in this town. You go
in without probable cause, they'll call it an illegal search...
你知道的或是他们没有教你这个？ or didn't they
teach you that in cop school?
别走开，我找到证据就会叫你
If I find some evidence, I'll come get you.
但你不能… - But you can't...
放心吧，如果有突发的事情我会来找你的 - But nothin'.Just be cool. If anything
jumps off, I'll get ya, all right? I promise, okay?.Thank you.
你可会让我独自进去？ Any chance you're gonna give
me that key and let me go in by myself?
不行 No chance.
该死，来吧 Fuck. Come on.
-看来他们已经来过 -你想找什么？ - Looks like they been here already.
- What exactly are you looking for?
这个，这个从外国来的箱子还没有通关的（加州比佛利山霍利斯本顿画廊） This. This is a crate
from overseas. Hasn't passed through customs yet.
这是什么？ What is that?
咖啡？ Coffee?
对，上面的是咖啡
Yeah, it's coffee on top.
但这个不是糖，叫罗斯伍德
This ain't sugar.Go get Rosewood.
欢迎参加这个派对 Welcome to the party.
我们有客人了 Seems we have guests.
真好，我喜欢惊喜
How nice. I do like surprises.
珍妮 Jeannette
我看到你在这里真是失望 I just can't tell you how
disappointed I am to find you here.
-维多，我… -闭嘴！
- Victor, listen, I... - Shut up!
我不想听 I don't want to hear it.
-带她到车上等我 -你会怎么样对待他？ Take her to the car and wait for me, okay?
What are you gonna do with him?
你应该担心我们会怎么对待你 I thinkyou should be more worried
about what we're going to do with you.
放心，我们有可卡因和咖啡，我们会开个大派对 Don't worry about me. We got cocaine
and coffee here. We're gonna get wired and have a big party.
谢谢你让我参加，真好 Thanks for havin' me
over, Vic.This is very nice.
你说什么吗？ Did you say something?
-如果她有什么不测… -我洗耳恭听 If somethin'
happens to her... I'm all ears.
-我会杀死你 -真的？那么有好戏看了 I'll kill you.
Really?.That would be a neat trick.
-老兄 -你还生我的气吗？ Well, cous'.
You still pissed at me?
不是，不过我早该在底特律把你解决掉 But I should have
taken care of you in Detroit...
在我射死你的朋友之后
when I popped your little buddy.
再见，福里先生， Good-bye, Mr. Foley.
祝你愉快 我尽量 - Have a nice day.
- I'll try.
该死 Damn it.
天 Oh, boy.
在底特律被我打到头肿的伤怎么了？ How's that little bump on
the head doin'I gave you in Detroit, huh?
痊癒得很好 Healed up nice, I hope.
别动！ Freeze!
谢谢你 Thanks, man.
叫塔格特查看那个仓库和随机应变，我稍后会作解释 Tell Taggart to check the
warehouse at that address. I'll explain later.
DD-6，塔格特队长在这里
DD-6, Sergeant Taggart is here now.
他想跟你说 -该死 -比利，到底什么事？ - He wants to talkk to you.
- Shit! - What the hell is goin' on?
-抱歉，队长，我现在不能谈 -什么意思？
- Sorry. Can't talk now. What mean You can't talk now?
你只管查看那个仓库，求你别跟博戈米尔说 Just check out the warehouse
and please don't say anything to Bogomil.
-他终止了通讯 -该死 Sorry, sir.He's not
transmitting anymore. shit
-什么事？ -比利又做傻事了 - What's the matter?
- Billy's doing something dumb again.I don't know what.
-他是否从饭店打来？ -不是
- Was he callin' from the hotel? - No, sir.
他的车正在棕峡路朝北方走 Right now his car is
heading north on Palm Canyon Road.
我们今早去过那里
We were there this morning.
-什么？ 福里去那里查看麦特兰的房子 - What?
- Yeah. Foley was up there looking over Maitland's house.
-你可有仓库的地址？ -有 You have the address of that warehouse?
- Yes, sir.
去那里查看一下把现场的情况告诉我 - Here. You two check that place out, then find me.
Let me know what the hell is goin' on over there.
除了我不可告诉别人
Don't talk to anybody but me.
别动，福里，你被拘捕了.比利，你干嘛在这里？ Hold it. You're under arrest.
What the hell are you doin' here?
我用枪强迫他的 I stole my gun and
forced him to bring me here.
不是，他说关于麦特兰的事都是对的 No, he didn't. Everything
he said about Maitland is right.
他绑架了一个女人, 她在这幢房子里 Now he's kidnapped a
woman, and he's got her in his house.
-我们去救她吧 -你以为我在干什么？ - Let's go and get her.
- What do you think I'm tryin' to do?
我们会处理的, 二十分鐘内我们会拿到搜查令 We'll handle this! We'll
have a search warrant here in 20 minutes.
-她二十分鐘内可能已死掉 -别动，你要跟我们走 -She'll be dead in 20 minutes.
- Stop workin' on the lock. Come with us.
我要进去, 你要制止我就开枪吧 I'm gonna open this door, and I'm goin' in.
You wanna stop me? Shoot me.
我也去，你要做什么都行, 但我要进去 Me too.You can do what
you want, but I'm goin' in with Axel.
这回真的很麻烦 Damn it, Billy.This
is really serious trouble.
你们走运的话只会被革职
If you're lucky, you'll just get fired.
-打开了 -福里，这是我的最后警告 Got it.
It's my last warning.
-比利 -对不起，队长，我必须如此 I'm sorry, Sarge.
I've got to.
该死，等一会 Shit. Wait a minute.
什么事？ What's that?
好像在东门 看一下 Looks like east gate.
Punch it up.
那他妈的是谁？ Who the hell is that?
去找麦特兰 Get Maitland.
所有人去了哪里？ Where is everybody?
欧文斯比，罗斯伍德回来了没有？ -没有
- Owensby, is Rosewood backyet? - No, sir.
-塔格特在吗？ 他十分鐘前出去了 - Have you seen Taggart?
- Took off about 10 minutes ago.
福里来了 Foley's on the grounds.
我他妈怎么知道？马上叫些人出去 How the hell should I
know?.Get some people out there right away.
留心盯著那个屏幕
Don't take your eyes off that screen.
设法找出塔格特和罗斯伍德的位置 I want you to try
to locate Taggart and Rosewood.
来吧 Come on.
Okey, okey… 好的…
Fuck! 该死！
-他们一定离开了车子 -我知道，继续试试 - They must be away from the car, sir.
- I can see that. Keep trying.
- DD-13，请通话 -他们的位置在哪里？
- DD-13, come in, please. - What's their 20?
-棕峡路609号 -谁住在那里？ 609 Palm Canyon Road.
Who lives at that address?
一个叫维多麦特兰的人
A Victor Maitland, sir.
再来 Try it again.
-我们绕过去吧 来，我们行的，快点 - Let's go around.
- Come on. - What are you doin'? - Come on.
准备，一、二… Ready? One, two...
三！ three!
没事吧？ You all right?
我他妈的来这里干嘛？
What the fuck am I doin' here?
把枪放下！ Drop it!
-射得好，比利 -我们走吧
- Good shot, Billy. - Let's go.
-天！ -这些傢伙是认真的 - Jesus Christ!
- These guys are serious.
我讨厌机枪 I hate machine guns.
掩护我 Cover me.
你们去前面，我去后面看看 You guys go around
front.I'm gonna check the back.
我们接报在同一个地点有枪声，棕峡路609号 Sir, we have a report of shots
fired at that same location.609 Palm Canyon Road.
发出通报，有警察需要支援
Put out a 998, officers need assistance.
-现场有内应 -长官？ Undercover is on the scene.
- Sir?
做吧，我要所有北区组员出动，南区组员留在原位 - Just do it. I want all north
units to roll. South units stay in their area.
该死！我们走吧 Damn. Let's go.
现场有内应探员
Undercover officers at location.
警察！你们被拘捕了！
Police! You're all under arrest!
你再这样做我就开枪射你
You do that again, I'll shoot you myself.
可知道我在想什么？
You know whatl keep thinking about?
你可知道[虎豹小霸王]的结局？
You know the end of Butch Cassidy?
瑞福和纽曼，差不多耗尽子弹 Redford and Newman
are almost out of ammunition.
整支玻利维亚军队在那间小屋门前 The whole Bolivian army
is out in front of this little hut.
比利…我会让你受到处分的
I'm gonna make you pay for this.
-你还要待在这里？ -才不要
- You gonna hang around here? - Fuck, no!
别动！ - Freeze!
- Hold it right there.
该死 Shit!
阿克塞尔！ Axel！
小伙子，小心点，它可能会射中我
Be careful, old boy.You might hit me.
别动！ Freeze!
警察！你们被拘捕了！
Police! You're all under arrest!
放下武器，高举双手，退后两步 Lay down your weapons in front of you!
Take two steps back with your hands up!
很好 好极 Very good. Great.
-这是什么回事？ -该死 What the
hell's going on here? Shit.
-这个人在这里干什么？ -流血，长官
- What's this man doing here? - Bleeding, sir.
罗斯伍德，为何他没有扣上手铐？
How come he isn't wearing handcuffs?
其实他不是被拘禁，长官
Well, he isn't actually in custody, sir.
快把他拘留，还是你想我动手？ Well, place him in
custody, or would you like me to do it?
长官，你想先听听我的报告吗 Wouldn't you like
to hear my report first, sir?
-你有解释这件事的报告？ -是的 You have a report
that explains all this? Yes, sir.
我乐意听听
Well, I will be very glad to hear it.
麦特兰画廊的经理珍妮桑玛斯小姐… Miss Jeannette Summers, the
manager of Mr. Maitland's art gallery...
在艺廊仓库无意中发现大量怀疑是… accidently discovered large amounts
of a substance she suspected was cocaine...
可卡因物品
in the gallery's warehouse.
她立刻把她的发现通知阿克塞尔福里探员 She communicated her discovery
to Detective Foley of the Detroit Police.
福里探员当时正在… Detective Foley was,
at the time, cooperating...
参与一项比佛利山和底特律合作的缉毒调查行动 in a joint Beverly Hills-Detroit
investigation of narcotics trafficking.
福里和罗斯伍德探员对桑玛斯小姐的报告作出回应 Detectives Foley and
Rosewood, responding to Miss Summers' report...
来到这个仓库，罗斯伍德在现场发现八十公斤可卡因 proceeded to the warehouse where Rosewood did...
in fact, discover approximately 80 kilos of cocaine.
罗斯伍德立刻召唤支援
Rosewood immediately called for backup.
我调派了警察来到这里
I dispatched our officers to this location.
塔格特队长是第一个抵达现场的 Sergeant Taggart here
was the first to arrive at the scene.
由于有充分的证据相信这里有罪案正在发生… Having probable cause
to believe a felony was in progress...
塔格特加入罗斯伍德的行动，福里只是旁观者… Sergeant Taggart joined Rosewood...
with Detective Foley present only as an observer...
他们进入现场
and proceeded to enter the grounds.
我们开枪自卫把几个疑匪射死，包括麦特兰先生 In the course of defending ourselves...
we shot several suspects, including Mr. Maitland.
你指望我会相信这个报告？
You expect me to believe that report?
这是我呈交的报告，长官
That's the report I'm filing, sir.
塔格特队长，不如你把实情告诉我吧 Sergeant Taggart,
why don't you tell me what happened?
局长，实情就如探长所说一样 Happened just like
the lieutenant said, Chief.
那么我得恭喜你们了 Well, I suppose
congratulations are in order.
谢谢，长官 Thank you.
明早把报告呈交给我吧 That report better
be on my desk in the morning.
知道，长官，第一件事。
Yes, sir, first thing.
你的谎话真了得
You were lyin' your ass off.
到医院检查你的肩膀吧 Why don't you go to the
hospital and get your shoulder looked at?
对不起，长官 Excuse me, sir.
你可否帮我一个忙？ I was wondering if
you could do me a favor, sir?
-你的人情已经用完了 -我明白 I thinkyour favors
are all used up. I understand.
我想请你打给我的老板陶德探员 I was hoping that you could call
on my Inspector Todd, my boss back home...
帮我澄清，但没关系，反正我也会失业 and straighten things out for me, but that's
all right.I guess I'm just out of a job. It's cool though.
我会留在比佛利山 I think I'm gonna stay in
Beverly Hills.I like it out here.
开一间私家侦探社 I'm gonna start my own
private investigation company.
我会跟陶德谈的，明天第一件事。 -真的？ I will talk to Inspector
Todd first thing tomorrow. - Will you really?
-是的 -谢谢你 - Yes, you bet.
- Thank you so much, sir. - You're welcome.
你好，我是阿克塞尔福里，办理1035号退房手续 How ya doin'? I'm
Axel Foley, checkin' out of suite 1035.
先生，请稍候 我去拿你的帐单 One moment, sir.
I'll get your bill.
你们不必来送我，但我很感动 Y'all didn't have to come see
me off, but I'm moved by the gesture. Thanks.
博戈米尔命令我们，要确保你离开本市 Bogomil ordered us
to make sure you got out of town.
不要紧，要紧的是 That doesn't even matter to me.
You know what matters?
你们来了，我很激动，喉咙也哽咽了 That you came. I'm all choked up.
I got a lump in my throat
你也眼泛泪光，塔格特
You look a little misty yourself there.
-先生，这里 -谢谢 - Here you go, sir.
- Thank you.
对不起，比佛利山警察局会支付帐单 Excuse me. The Beverly
Hills Police Department is picking that up.
真不敢相信，不会是真的吧，你们太好了 Get outta here. Guys, that's the
last straw.That was the last straw.You are too nice.
你们的浴袍出售吗？ Sir, do you sell those
Beverly Palm robes down here?
-卖的，每件95块 -钱不是问题，算进我的帐单 Yes, we do, sir.They're $95 apiece.
Money's no object. Put them on my tab.
我要买两件 I need two.
比利，你救了我一命，我不知道可有机会报答你 You saved my life. I
don't think I'll ever be able to repay you.
但为了表示我的谢意，我要你收下这件舒适的浴袍 But as a token of my
appreciation, I want you to have this fine robe.
你这辈子每次洗澡时，都会想起我们的友谊 Each time you shower and
you're dripping wet, think of our friendship.
我要你想起阿克塞尔福里 我爱你，比利 I want you to think
about Axel Foley. I love you, Billy.
谢谢，阿克塞尔 Thanks, Axel.
让我拿吧，你的胳膊该休息一下
Let me take this. You should rest that arm.
比利，结帐吧
Take care of the tab, would you?
-塔格特… -这里，先生 Taggart
Here you are.
送给你的 This is for you.
不用了，你留作纪念吧
That's all right.You keep it as a souvenir.
我袋里已经有三件了
I already have three of them in my bag.
-这里 -谢谢你，先生 There you go.
Take it easy.
不说声再见吗？ -你们不是要跟著我到边境吗 You're not gonna say good-bye?
Ain't you guys gonna tail me to the city limits anyway?
-是的 -我猜你们会的 Yes, we are.
I figured you would.
我想停下来去喝杯酒 I was thinking about stopping
off and getting something to drink.
- 我们猜你会的-你们可会陪我去？
- We sort of figured you would.- That mean you're gonna join me?
不了，我们仍在值班
I don't think so. We're still on duty.
我相信一杯啤酒不会害死我们的，比利 Well, I don't think
one beer's gonna kill us, Billy.
对，听塔格特的话，放松点
That's right.Listen to Taggart. Lighten up.
一杯啤酒不会害死我们的
One drink's not gonna kill us.
但要是你们落后得太远，不要害怕，按喇叭知道吗？ Hey, guys... if you fall
too far behind, don't be afraid to honk, okay?
我们去哪里？ Where we goin' anyway?
放心，跟着我就行了
Don't worry about it. Just follow my lead.
我知道有个好地方，你们会喜欢的，相信我吧 I know the perfect
place.You guys will love it. Trust me.